Frank Pigeon

IT Specialist (SYSANALYSIS) at AMEDDC&S

frank.pigeonjr@gmail.com

Summary

With over 15 years of IT experience, I'm looking to broaden my horizons into web and mobile development. I'm a U.S. Army veteran, hold a SECRET clearance, and have a Bachelor's Degree in Management, CIS. Fluent in English and Spanish, a focused team player, lifetime learner, heart of a teacher, and excited to take on new challenges that combine my creativity and business sense.

Certifications

- * CompTIA Project +
- * CompTIA Security+
- * CompTIA A+
- * CCNA

Specialties

- * Web Development
- * Project Management
- * Digital Media

Experience

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer at Self-Employed

May 2014 - Present (3 months)

Platform/Environment: Hypertext Markup Language (HTML), Linux, Mac OSX, VirtualBox, Vagrant, Ansible, Apache, mySQL, PHP, Git, GitHub, JavaScript, jQuery, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Bootstrap framework, WordPress Content Management System (CMS), Laravel Framework, Moment.js API, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, and Adobe Premiere Pro.

- * Design, develop, and maintain web sites and applications using the LAMP Stack.
- * Maintain web site for Hope Arise United Methodist Church using the WordPress CMS.
- * Design and develop web games using Javascript and JQuery.

IT Project Manager, Operations Training Support, G6, US Army Medical Department Center and School at United States Department of Defense

June 2010 - Present (4 years 2 months)

Provides project management support during the planning, development, testing and implementation of new systems in support of the Army Medical Department, Military Health Systems, and the Medical Command. Support includes project planning, control, reporting, risk management, scheduling, tracking, variance analysis and administrative support throughout the life cycle of the project.

Develops the five year business plan for infrastructure refresh in conformance with established capital planning procedures and CIO guidance. Has knowledge of and is skilled in network systems design, development, testing, installation, operations, management, and maintenance concepts and methods.

Recommends and implements creative and innovative SharePoint solutions to AMEDDC&S G6 technical staff. Creates or modifies web parts and database-driven components, including document libraries, dashboards, and work flows on the G6 SharePoint portal.

IT Specialist, Operations Support, G6, US Army Medical Department Center and School at United States Department of Defense

March 2008 - June 2010 (2 years 4 months)

Coordinates deployment services provided by the local Network Enterprise Center (NEC) to AMEDDC&S functional users. Manages AMEDDC&S involvement in the initial deployment, subsequent movement, and technology refresh of computer equipment, printers, copiers, and telephones.

Forward Deployed Tech at Decypher

June 2006 - February 2008 (1 year 9 months)

Responsible for the daily operations of the Information Management Office as resident technical expert on all ADPE (Automated Data Processing Equipment), communications products, and audio / visual equipment, and networks assigned to the DMRTI command spanning four buildings and two installations (Ft. Sam Houston and Camp Bullis) in a senior joint military environment.

Systems Engineer at Directorate of Information Management

March 2005 - June 2006 (1 year 4 months)

Responsible for the deployment, installation, configuration, and operation of all IT equipment acquired through the DOIM working independently or on a team of IT specialists in a dynamic, fast paced environment while maintaining DOD (Department of Defense) standards and guidelines. Installed, configured, repaired, deployed, troubleshoot personal computers and peripheral devices, and operating systems.

Systems Research Specialist at USARSO

July 2004 - March 2005 (9 months)

Assisted the U.S. Army South (USARSO) G6 staff to implement / maintain program management over command and control systems for the USARSO headquarters.

Identified, compiled, analyzed and made recommendations for the system design and system integration to meet the present and future needs of USARSO. Assisted in C4 policy development and strategic planning for the USARSO headquarters.

SSG at US Army

1997 - 2003 (6 years)

Served in various positions during military career:

- Information Technology Center Supervisor, Chief Information Office, Carlisle Barracks, PA

- Information Technology Team Leader, Directorate of Strategic Systems, U.S. Army War College
- Computer Technician, Directorate of Educational Technology, Ft. Leavenworth, KS
- Computer Operator Analyst (74B)

Projects

Github

May 2014 to Present

Members:Frank Pigeon

CodeUp project repositories.

Organizations

Geekdom

Member

May 2014 to Present

SATLUG

December 2013 to Present

San Antonio Linux User Group

Volunteer Experience

Worship & Communications Team at Hope Arise UMC

January 2012 - December 2013 (2 years)

Maintain church website, social media presence, edit and upload weekly sermons to YouTube, worked with the worship team.

Languages

Spanish

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Courses

Computer Science

Regis University

Operating Systems Concepts Principles of Programming

Control Structures

CS361

IT Project Manager, Operations Training Support, G6, US Army Medical Department Center and School

United States Department of Defense

CompTIA Project+ Certification (2009 Objectives)
Westlake training and development: Project
Management Fundamentals and Project Management
Risk Management
SharePoint Designer

Skills & Expertise

PHP

Laravel

MySQL

HTML

CSS

jQuery

Web Development

Project Management

SharePoint

CompTIA

CompTIA Project+ Certification

CompTIA A+ Certification

CompTIA Security+ Certification

Security Clearance

Military Experience

Information Assurance

Network Architecture

Government Contracting

Active DoD Secret Clearance

Adobe Creative Suite

Wordpress

Linux

C++

Troubleshooting

Integration

Certifications

Project+ Certified Professional

CompTIA License 10489480 June 2011

Security + Certified Professional

CompTIA License 10489480 August 2008

A + Certified Computer Technician

CompTIA License 10489480 May 2001

Cisco Certified Network Associate

Cisco License CSCO10495050 June 2001 to June 2005

Education

CodeUp

Web Development using the LAMP stack, Computer Science, 2014 - 2014

Activities and Societies: Geekdom member 1 recommendation available upon request

Regis University

Computer Science, 2012 - 2013

Park University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Management, CIS, 2004 - 2012

Grade: 3.85/4.0

Activities and Societies: Magna Cum Laude

Kansas City Kansas Community College

Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), Computer Information Systems, 2001 - 2003

Grade: 3.94/4.0

Balboa High School

Interests

new technologies, Linux, open source, web development and design, mobile apps development.

Frank Pigeon

IT Specialist (SYSANALYSIS) at AMEDDC&S

frank.pigeonjr@gmail.com



1 person has recommended Frank

"I would highly recommend Frank based on our time working at Hope Arise UMC together. Frank has volunteered his time as our website manager/editor. He engaged in regular upkeep of our website and even designed and implemented various pages for our site. Frank provided an indispensable service to the church, in maintaining our web content as current and accurate. This is a common problem with church websites, as they often are design heavy and lack adequate upkeep. Therefore many churches have very stale websites with loads of inaccurate and dated information. Thanks to Franks hard work, we never had these issues during his time with Hope Arise UMC. Therefore, I highly recommend Frank Pigeon! Reese Henry III Senior Pastor, Hope Arise UMC"

— Reese Henry, Senior Pastor, Hope Arise UMC, advised Frank at CodeUp

Contact Frank on LinkedIn